SONIA SUNWAR

https://soniasunwar.github.io/sonia-portfolio/ Oxford, Open to relocating | soniasunwar@live.co.uk | 07455993135

PERSONAL STATEMENT

UX Researcher/ Designer with a background in Structural Design in the Civil Engineering industry. Experienced in dealing with stakeholders, evaluating user research to create user-centric designs, supporting programmes and delivering projects to meet strict time, cost and quality requirements.

SKILLS AND TOOLS

- Competitive Analysis
- User Research
- User Journeys
- User Flows
- User Persona

- Information Architect
- Wireframing
- Affinity Mapping
- Prototyping
- Accessibility

- HTML
- **CSS**
- Figma
- VSCode
- GitHub

UX PROJECTS

Thailo Apr 2021 - Feb 2022

- Created "Thailo," a responsive mobile banking prototype app, featuring services like money transfer, e-wallet, budgeting, and savings functionality.
- Performed competitive analysis and user research to identify user pain points and uncover new opportunities.
- Developed over 50 low-fidelity wireframes as a concept design, which evolved into high-fidelity designs following WCAG standards, and created style pattern assets to ensure design consistency.
- Conducted more than 10 in-person and remote usability tests, including A/B preference testing, and gathered valuable user feedback.
- Analysed user feedback through methods like affinity mapping and rainbow spreadsheets, resulting in a user-centric design approach.

Learn & Grow Mar 2021 - Apr 2021

- Designed a vocabulary-learning app that allows users to learn a new language by listening to and reading stories.
- Conducted user interviews, preparing research goals and survey questions to gain insights into user pain points.
- Created user flows to determine the necessary pages and screens within the app to accommodate the user's
- Performed scenario and direct task user interviews using a low-fidelity prototype to assess navigation usability.
- Assessed user feedback using Jakob Nielsen's rating scale, prioritising major issues for immediate resolution before the app's launch.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Computer-Aided Design (CAD) Technician

Cluttons Beta Design Consultants

Dec 2021 - Current Jul 2019 - Nov 2021

- Participate in the entire end-to-end user journey, from concept design to the as-built phase, integrating feedback from engineers, clients, and site findings to maintain up-to-date designs, with a primary focus on ensuring timely project progression and completion.
- Proactively engage in technical discussions with engineers and surveyors, actively sharing observations and insights to identify and validate effective design solutions.
- Collaborate with project leaders, surveyors, and engineers to ensure that designs align with client requirements and site conditions while maintaining consistency and adhering to industry and company guidelines.
- Facilitate client satisfaction by addressing structural queries and accommodating changing demands through effective communication.
- Demonstrate a commitment to learning new tools like CADS RC for ongoing projects and continuously seek ways to enhance productivity.

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS